Bernadus Maria Rosario Hardus Tukan

Klitren Lor GK II, Gondokusuman • Kota Yogyakarta, 55222

• tukanbernad@gmail.com • +62 821 9857 8051

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hardus-tukan-78857317b/

Github: https://github.com/Berndzz

Summary

I am a graduate of Computer Science from Duta Wacana Christian University, with an interest in Android programming, UX Design, problem solving, and REST API. I am dedicated and willing to learn new knowledge, adaptable to work both in teams and individually. I also enjoy the latest android technology, such as Jetpack Compose, from my learning experience at Dicoding Indonesia. I have obtained several certifications from SIB Dicoding and Dicoding Challenge, such as Fundamental Android Learning, Intermediate Android Application Development Learning, and Creating Android Applications with Jetpack Compose Learning.

Education

Duta Wacana Christian University

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics.
Thesis: Text Summarization For Indonesian Articles On The Corpus Of Cultural Objects

Using The Lexrank Method

• Participated in Dicoding Developer Conference (DDC) 2023

Experience

SIB Dicoding Indonesia

Android Developer (Capstone Project)

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

Aug 2018 - Nov 2022

- Project: TMDB Movie App
- Skill: Kotlin, MVVM, Firebase, Git, Room, Pagination, Dependency Injection (Hilt)
- Tools: Android Studio, Firebase Console, TMDB Api

Android Developer - Fundamental Android

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

- Projectt: GithubUser Api App
- Skill: Kotlin, MVVM, Room, Git
- Tools : Android Studio, Github Api

Android Developer - Intermediate Android

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

- Projectt: Story App
- Skill: Kotlin, MVVM, Room, Git, Dependency Injection (Hilt)
- Tools: Android Studio, Dicoding Storp Api

UX Designer

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

- Projectt: ITa Prototype
- Skill: Wireframe, Prototyping, Design Thinking
- Tools: Figma, Maze, Sharpen, Microsoft Excel

Dicoding Challenge

Android Developer - Jetpack Compose

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

- Project : Clash of Clans Statue App
- Skill: Kotlin, MVVM, Room, Git, Room,
- Tools: Android Studio, Jetpack UI

DIGITAL TALENT SCHOLARSHIP

Trainee - Big Data Using Python (FGA)

Jul 2022 - Aug 2022

- Learn Fundamental Python, Data Analysis and Storytelling With Data
- For the final project, I have created an application called "MyToDoList" with features such as CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations and the ability to print the TODO items.

SEKOLAH TINGGI TEOLOGI & FILSAFAT Fajar Timur (STFT)

Web Developer - (SIAKAD Website)

Mar 2023 - Apr 2023

• Skill: PHP, Codeigniter 4, MVC, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Git

• Tools: VsCode, Bootstrap, AdminLTE Template

DUTA WACANA CHRISTIAN UNIVERSITY

Assistant Researcher May 2022 - Sep 2022

Bernadus Maria Rosario Hardus Tukan

- Created a text summarization application for multiple documents using the Streamlit framework in Python
- Helping informatics lecturers collect data for the creation of Indonesian cultural web portals (Semantic Web)

Assistant - Data Entry Mar 2021 - Aug 2021

- Input data related to cultural objects in Indonesia into the cultural corpus management website.
- Helped informatics lecturer to collected data for creating semantic web

Leadership & Activities

DWPRO - DWCU

Decoration Division Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

• Decorating the entrance and event stage for Healthy Walk Color Fun. Apart from that, we were also tasked with making banners and souvenirs during a visit to Hellen Keller Indonesia SLB.

Skills & Interests

Technical: Kotlin (Android Native, Jetpack Compose), Git, UX Design, MVVM, RestApi, Python, NLP, Microsoft Office, Figma, Firebase, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Wireframe, Prototyping

Language: Indonesia, English

Skill: Time management, Teamwork, Communication, Problem Solving, Creative Thinking

Certification: Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Android untuk Pemula, Memulai Pemrograman Dengan Kotlin, Pengenalan ke Logika Pemrograman (Programming Logic 101), Belajar Fundamental Aplikasi Android, Belajar Prinsip Pemrograman SOLID, IT Specialist - HTML and CSS, Meniti Karier sebagai Software Developer, Belajar Dasar UX Design, Belajar Pengembangan Aplikasi Android Intermediate, Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Android dengan Jetpack Compose, Belajar Dasar Git dengan GitHub, Pemrograman Kotlin: Pemula sampai Mahir

Interest: Mobile Programing, UI/UX Designer, NLP